你在被监视着
You are being watched.
政府有一套秘密系统
The government has a secret system--
一台每时每刻都在监视你的机器
a machine that spies on you every hour of every day.
我会知道  因为它是我造的
I know because... I built it.
我设计这台机器是为了侦测恐怖活动
I designed the machine to detect acts of terror
但它却看到了一切
but it sees everything--
它看到了与普通人相关的暴力罪行
Violent crimes involving ordinary people.
像你一样的普通人
People like you.
而政府认为这些罪行无关紧要
Crimes the government considered irrelevant.
他们不肯作为  所以我决定插手
They wouldn't act, so I decided I would.
但我需要一个搭档
But I needed a partner.
一个有能力介入其中的人
Someone with the skills to intervene.
因为受当局追捕  我们只能秘密合作
Hunted by the authorities, we work in secret.
你永远找不到我们
You will never find us.
不管你是被害人还是行凶者  如果你的号码被列出来
But victim or perpetrator, if your number's up,
我们就会找到你
we'll find you.
疑犯追踪 第1季 第7集
Person of Interest S01E07 720p HDTV x264
字幕翻译：YYeTs人人影视
电话来了  目标已锁定
The call came in. We have a location on the target.
多叫几个人  我马上过去和你们汇合
Get a team, and I'll meet you there.
我们能搞定
We can handle this.
不  我必须亲自去
No. I want to be there in person.
我要亲自杀了他
I want to kill him myself.
等等  那段倒回去重看一遍
Wait. Can you rewind that for me?
我以为我加入了重案组后
I thought I was all done mopping up bodega shootings
就不用再街杂货店打砸抢的案子了
when I joined the homicide task force.
你觉得这是抢劫案吗
This looks like a stickup job to you?
那你还是回去接着做巡警吧
Then maybe you need to go back to working a precinct.
歹徒没拿走钱
There was no money taken.
快速两发连射  近距离射击  凶手的目的是杀人
Double tap, close range-- this was an execution.
知道死者是谁了吗
We got any I.D. on the vic?
还不知道  但你没看到最重要的部分
Not yet, but you haven't seen the best part.
重放一遍
Rewind it again.
有个目击者
We got ourselves a witness.
-找到他了吗  -我派了人
- Any sign of him? - I put out a bolo.
排查了方圆里六个街区
Had a team canvass a six-block radius.
那家伙消失了
Guy vanished.
换我也会吓得藏起来
I'd make myself scarce too.
你可不想在这一带的人当做是告密者
This ain't no neighborhood you want to be called a snitch.
-可不是  - 警探...
- No, it's not. - Detective...
外面围着一群记者想知道内部消息
Got a bunch of reporters out there begging me for scraps.
我怎么跟他们说
What do I tell them?
让他们去找公关组的人
Send them to the task force P.R. guy.
-让他去应付  -好的  长官
- Let him deal with them. - Yes, ma'am.
舍曼斯基探员  集团犯罪科的
Detective Szymanski, organized crime,
-这位是弗斯科探员  -幸会
- This is detective Fusco. - Nice to meet you.
这是黑帮干的吗
Was this a mob hit?
死者是"我们的家"的前任副手
The victim's a former "la cosa nostra" lieutenant
名叫本尼・达格斯蒂诺
By the name of Benny d'Agostino.
他很久不混这个圈子了
He was out of the game for a couple of years,
但六个月前他又开始活跃了
and then he popped up again on our radar about six months ago.
布莱顿海滩是俄罗斯黑帮的地盘
Brighton beach is Russian territory.
"我们的家"的人跑来干嘛
So what's the l.C.N. doing here?
你不知道吗  这儿马上要开战了
You kidding? There's a war going on.
上周以来有一半俄罗斯黑帮的元老
Half a dozen V.I.P.S. in the Russian mob
都被清理了
were taken out last month.
听说幕后黑手是本尼的老大
Word is Benny's boss ordered the hits.
-他要来复仇  -他老大是谁
- This was retribution. - So who's his boss?
我们知道的不多
We don't know much...
只知道他叫以利亚
Other than a name-- Elias.
你听过吗
You heard of him?
太听过了  我们是老相识了
Oh, yeah. We go way back.
上礼拜他的手下刚和我照过面
One of his guys took a shot at me last week.
这个以利亚是个狡猾的混蛋
This Elias is a clever bastard.
没人知道他长什么样
Nobody even knows what he looks like.
那个目击者呢
What about the witness?
你的手下找到他了吗
Your boys have any luck finding him?
没有  不过再看看监控录像
No, but have another look at the surveillance footage.
死者跟目击者说了点什么
The victim said something to the witness.
如果这是临终遗言  他还透露了凶手的名字
If it's a dying declaration and he named the killers,
那也解释的通
it'd be admissible.
是的  不过我们还有个麻烦
Yeah, but we've got a problem.
我们亲爱的俄罗斯老板
The Russian owner of this fine establishment
事发当时
was on a conveniently timed smoke break
正好跑出去抽烟了
when all this went down.
他坚持说他什么也不知道
He's not giving us anything.
你觉得他会告诉凶手吗
You think he told the shooters we found a witness?
如果他说了  那俄罗斯黑帮为了找到目击者
If he did, the Russians will knock down every door
一定会把这一带掀个底朝天
in this neighborhood till they find him.
我的人会继续在这一带排查
Well, my guys are working the block.
-希望能查到什么  -但愿
- Something will pop. - It better.
我们得赶在俄国人之前找到他
We got to get to this witness before the Russians do.
我昨晚收到了他的号码
I received his number late last night.
他叫查理・伯顿
His name is Charlie Burton.
他看上去很不安
The guy is worried about something.
但我暂时没发现威胁
I'm not seeing a threat yet.
他是什么情况  芬奇
What's his story, Finch?
他是个高中历史老师
He's a high-school history teacher
在布莱顿海滩区的中学教书
working in the Brighton Beach school district.
独居  从没结过婚
Lives alone, never married--
没有其他的了
not much to go on.
没准有学生在追杀他
Well, maybe a student's after him.
你懂  教书可是个很危险的职业
You know, teaching can be a dangerous profession.
是呀  我觉得当间谍要安全多了
Yes, I imagine espionage was a much safer choice,
里瑟先生
Mr. Reese.
你好  莱奈尔
Hello, Lionel.
我不清楚你平时是怎么工作的
I'm not sure how you usually do what you do,
但我正在找一个人  需要你的帮助
But I'm looking for a guy, and I could use some help.
他是个目击者  目击了俄罗斯帮派的枪杀
He's a witness, saw a Russian mob hit go down.
白种人  身高五英寸十英尺左右  秃顶
He's caucasian, 5'10", bald.
在班上不是那种起眼的类型
Probably not the most popular guy in his class,
你懂的吧
If you know what I mean.
我们得找到他
We need to find him.
我想我已经找到了
I think I already did.
为啥我一点都不惊讶
Why am I not surprised?
听着  不管谁是凶手
Listen, whoever did this hit,
他们肯定会去找他
They're gonna come looking for him.
他们已经来找他了
They've already found him.
里瑟先生...
Mr. Reese...
我们把这个问题交给执法机关解决吧
We might want to leave this one to the authorities.
来不及了  我立刻行动
No time. I'm heading in.
封锁出口
Cover the exits.
其余的跟我来
The rest of you come with me.
■
本字幕由 YYeTs人人影视 原创翻译制作
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新 请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
翻译：路德维希船长 goldencui Tiberius 海因里希舰长
■
时间轴：烟幕迟迟  后期：灰灰是菇凉
校对&总监：海因里希舰长
■
从我家滚出去
Get out of my apartment.
伯顿先生  你有危险
Mr. Burton, you're in danger.
杂货店的那伙人来找你了
The men from the bodega are here.
你怎么知道  他们派你来的吗
Now, how do you know about that? Did they send you?
先生  现在有一票俄罗斯杀手逼近了
Sir, you have a Russian hit team closing in,
在你做决定之前
Which leaves us with approximately five seconds
我们大概还有五秒钟时间
before you need to make a decision.
我怎么知道你跟他们不是一伙
How do I know you're not one of them?
因为我都站在你眼前了
Because I'm standing in front of you
你还好端端地活着
And you're still alive.
看来我别无选择了
Doesn't seem like I've got a choice.
那傻逼跑哪儿去了
Where did this piece of garbage go?
我原路返回找
I'll double back.
里瑟先生  你能安全撤退吗
Mr. Reese, can you get out?
需要我报警吗
Do you need me to call in a distraction?
我回头再打给你  快来
Let me get back to you on that. Come on.
接着走
Let's get moving...
来
Now.
离开这个街区最快的方法
Okay, the fastest way out of this neighborhood
就是穿过这些楼
is through those buildings.
啥  你开玩笑呢吧
What, are you joking?
连俄国佬都不去乱闯那栋廉价房
Even the Russians don't go into the Double "B"s.
那是保加利亚毒贩的地盘
A bulgarian drug dealer runs the place.
芬奇  我需要另一条撤离路线
Okay, Finch, I'm gonna need another route out of here.
现在咱们孤立无援了  我要用你的手机
We're on our own. I need your cell phone.
我这人不用手机
I don't believe in them.
里瑟先生  听得到吗
Mr. Reese, can you hear me?
喂  这不是我的车
Hey, this isn't mine!
也不是我的  上车
Not mine either. Get in.
在咱们一块因为偷车入狱之前
May I at least have your name
至少告诉我你叫啥吧
Before we commit grand theft auto together?
首先  我们得把你弄到警察局去
First, we need to get you to the police,
把你在杂货店里看到的都告诉他们
So you can tell them about what you saw at the bodega.
俄罗斯黑帮在追杀我  老兄
The Russian mob is after me, friend.
他们在局里有眼线
They've got people on the inside.
我说了就死定了
If I testify, I'm dead.
我认识一个信得过的警探
I know a detective we can trust.
不过我们得先把你送到河对岸的曼哈顿去
But we need to get you across the river to Manhattan.
趴下
Get down!
我们得快走了
We need to keep moving.
这有点小麻烦了
That's going to be a problem.
你说俄国佬从不敢进去吗
You say the Russians don't go in there?
那我们进去
Well, that's where we're going.
我没说错吧
See what I mean?
这太疯狂了
This is crazy.
我还不知道你是谁
I still don't even know who you are.
我提供帮助
I help people.
你需要帮助
And you need help.
好吧
Well...
子弹直接穿过去了
Bullet went straight through clean--
没伤到骨头
No bone damage.
不过还是得清理一下伤口以防感染
But we need to get you cleaned up before it gets infected.
附近有药房吗
You see a pharmacy nearby?
你昨晚在杂货店看到的事情
The men you saw last night at the bodega...
你认识他们吗
what can you tell me about them?
这有什么区别
What difference does it make?
我想我得对想杀我的人
I guess I like to know a little bit about the guys
有点了解
who are shooting at me.
我加班到晚上  一直在批改作业
I worked through dinner, and I was grading papers.
回家路上在一家商店逗留了一下
And I stopped at the store on my way home.
我在犹豫是买蔬菜通心粉汤还是买豌豆汤
I couldn't decide between minestrone and split pea.
突然看到几个拿枪的人  我就躲起来了
And then I saw the guys with guns, and I hid.
你看到他们的脸了吗
Did you see their faces?
他们戴了面具
They had masks.
可有个人取下了面具
But one of them lifted his,
好像他故意让那个人看清他的脸
like he wanted that guy to see his face.
他们杀的那个人
But that guy they killed...
说他有口信要告诉个叫以利亚的人
He said he had a message for someone named Elias.
他想让我去帮他捎口信  可我不认识以利亚
And he wanted me to give it to him, but I don't know an Elias.
我跟他说了我不认识
I tried to tell him that.
伯顿先生  你让你带什么口信
Mr. Burton, what was the message?
我听不懂  和维尼有关的什么事
I didn't understand it-- something about Vinnie.
维尼会帮他完成工作
Vinnie was gonna finish the job for him.
你为什么不报警
Why didn't you call the police?
这片街区的规矩你不懂
You don't understand this neighborhood, do you?
找警察就像是赌轮盘
Going to the cops here is like playing Russian roulette.
你不知道哪个警察是他们的人
You don't know which side they're on.
我一个学生的父母去年报了警
One of my students' parents filed a police report last year.
结果就出了事故
Then he got into an accident.
到现在还在靠吸管进食
He's still eating through a straw.
我认识个可以信任的警官
I'll get you to a police officer you can trust.
我会闭紧嘴巴
I'm gonna keep my mouth shut
但愿事情就这么过去了
and hope it all blows over.
我也不知  这帮人看起来很生气
I don't know. These guys look pretty upset.
我要是去作证了
If I testify...
我就再也回不来了
I never get to come back here.
我那么努力地工作
And I've worked too hard.
这里就是我的家
This is my home.
至少为了我的学生  我不能离开他们
My students, for starters-- I-I can't leave them.
他们需要我
They need me.
你要是死了  伯顿先生
Well, you won't do those kids any good
学生们可就更指望不上你了
if you're dead, Mr. Burton.
叫我查理  学生才叫我伯顿先生
Charlie, please-- "Mr. Burton" Is for my students.
你想死吗  查理
Do you want to die, Charlie?
这可不是历史课
Because this isn't a history lesson.
这是真刀真枪
Those bullets are real.
我叫约翰
My name is John.
多谢你救我一命  约翰
Thank you for saving my ass, John.
多谢你来这一趟  帕蒂
Thanks for coming down, Patti.
对你丈夫的去世表示遗憾
We're all very sorry for your loss.
你才不遗憾  你恨透我丈夫了
You're not sorry. You hated my husband.
不  我只是恨他做的事
No, I only hated what he did for a living.
夫人
Ma'am...
你知不知道本尼昨晚为什么去布莱顿海滩
Do you know why Benny was in Brighton Beach last night?
他在那边是不是有生意上的事
Was he--I don't know-- conducting business?
达格斯蒂诺夫人
Mrs. D'agostino...
我明白你此时心中的愤怒
I know that anger you're feeling right now--
失去所爱的人是种什么感受
What it's like to lose someone you love.
帮我们抓住杀害你丈夫的人
Help us find the men who did this to your husband.
你们能不能找到他们无所谓
It doesn't matter if you find them.
Elias会找到他们
Elias will.
他会杀光每一个俄国混蛋
And he'll kill each and every single one of those russian bastards.
以利亚挑起了这场战争  可是他赢不了
Elias started a war that can't be won.
要是继续这样  很多无辜的人会送命
Now, a lot of innocent people are gonna die if this continues.
-你希望这样吗  -如果有必要的话
- Do you want that? - If that's what it takes.
他在哪儿  帕蒂
Where is he, Patti?
以利亚在哪
Where is Elias?
我从没见过他
I never met him.
他的手下也从不抛头露面
And his crew... they don't socialize.
所以你们永远找不到他
That's why you'll never find him.
我有一点疑惑
I'm a little confused.
为什么以利亚这么想得到布莱顿海滩
Why does Elias want Brighton Beach so bad?
你根本毫无头绪
You're not seeing it.
布莱顿海滩只是个开始
Brighton Beach is just the beginning.
以利亚有更宏大的计划
Elias has bigger plans.
他将会联合五大家族
He'll reunite the five families
肃清这帮俄国人渣
and take out the Russian trash.
当他大功告成时
And then when he's finished,
你们都将听命于他
you people will be answering to him.
五六个持有重型火力的人
Five or six heavily armed men were chasing a guy
在追一个符合我们目击者外貌的人
matching the description of our witness.
他名叫查理・伯顿
His name's Charlie Burton, by the way.
那家杂货店每个月给他送两次货
Found out he had groceries delivered twice a month from the bodega,
他不是一个人在逃命
And he wasn't dodging bullets by himself.
-他跟谁在一起  -一个高个西装男
- Who was he with? - Some tall guy in a suit--
绝对不是和俄国人一伙的
Definitely not with the Russians.
逃走前打中了一个俄国人的膝盖
Shot one of them in the knee before they got away.
怎么  你认识他
What? You know him?
这人我追踪了有一阵子了
It's just someone I've been tracking for a while.
我遇上的最厉害的  有军事背景
Best I've got, he's former military--
十足的麻烦
a pain in the ass.
他俩有人中弹吗
Either one of them get hit?
似乎交火很激烈啊
There seems to be an awful lot of shots fired.
他们似乎平安逃脱了
Looks like they got off okay.
一个俄国流氓被送进了医院  不过不肯开口
I got a russian thug in the hospital who isn't talking,
不过我们有街对面ATM机上的摄像头
But we got an ATM camera across the street.
或许能帮我们理清点头绪
That might help shed some light on things.
我得花两周弄到搜查证才能看到录像
It'll take two weeks and a warrant to get the footage.
幸运的是  一个路人给我们提供了她的录像
Thankfully, a bystander got some footage of her own.
这是彼得・约格洛夫
Meet Peter Yogorov.
和俄国黑帮老大伊万・约格洛夫是什么关系
As in Ivan Yogorov, the Russian boss?
彼得是他儿子
Peter's his son.
-警官  -是
- Yo, officer. - Yeah.
打给第八分局
Call over to the 8th.
叫他们找出任何与伊万・约格洛夫有关的文件
Tell them to pull any file we have pertaining to Ivan Yogorov.
伊万・约格洛夫  好的
Ivan Yogorov-- got it.
里瑟先生  你在哪儿
Where are you, Mr. Reese?
这些人是谁
Who are these guys?
这个警察和他们在一起干什么
And what's this cop doing with them?
纽约警局
N.Y.P.D.
-弗斯科警探  -警探你好
-Detective Fusco. - Hello, Detective.
我得和你谈谈我们共同的朋友
I need to talk to you about our mutual friend.
你是谁
Who's this?
我们共同的朋友是谁
And who the hell is our mutual friend?
提示一下  有一次你要带他去牡蛎湾
I seem to recall you were going to take him to oyster bay once upon a time.
你是他的手下吗
So you're his guy?
不  警探  你才是他的手下
No, Detective. I think that's your role.
我跟他失去了联系
I've lost contact with him.
你知道他和那个目击者在哪儿吗
Do you have any idea where he and the witness are now?
布莱顿海滩的某处
Yeah, somewhere in Brighton Beach.
俄国人在光天化日之下朝他们开火了
The Russians opened fire on them in broad daylight.
这种情况下他俩跑不远
Those two are going nowhere fast with this type of heat on them.
不幸的是  俄国黑帮
Unfortunately, the Russian mafia
恐怕不是我们唯一的麻烦
May not be our only problem.
我要你帮我查一个牌照
I need you to run a license plate for me.
好的  伙计  我会帮你
Yeah, sure, pal. I'll help you out...
只要你告诉我这究竟是怎么回事
If you can tell me what the hell it is I'm doing.
和你的案子有关  你知道这些就够了
It relates to your case. That's all you need to know.
TNF0818
"Tnf0818."
要是有我们朋友的消息
If I hear anything about our friend,
我怎么联系你
How do I get in touch with you?
你不用找我  我会找到你
You don't. I'll find you, detective.
告诉你  我能解决这家伙
I'm telling you, I winged the guy.
咱们进去结果了他
Let's get in there and finish him off.
拉斯洛  等等  我们得给爸爸打电话
Laszlo, wait up. We need to call papa, regroup.
你就这么在外面等着吗
You want to wait around out here?
好吧  我进去
Fine. I'm going in.
你想给保加利亚人的弹弓打吗
You want to go at it with a bunch of Bulgarian tweakers?
我们之前有协议
We made a deal--
井水不犯河水
They stay out of our territory. We stay out of theirs.
看住所有出口
Cover every exit.
那两个人想出来必须经过我们
No way those two get out without going past us first.
我要你保持清醒  查理
I need you to stay awake, charlie.
我可不希望你休克了
I don't want you to go into shock.
你究竟是怎么干上现在这一行的  约翰
So how did you wind up doing whatever it is you do, john?
事情  很复杂
It's... Complicated.
你呢
What about you?
你早就立志做老师吗
Did you always want to be a teacher?
不  我换了很多职业
No, it was sort of a career shift.
我很喜欢孩子
I came to like the kids a lot.
很多孩子的家长和俄国黑帮有联系
A lot of their parents are affiliated with the russian mob,
我希望给他们另外指一条路
So I try to give them other options.
他们有你真是福气
They're lucky to have you.
只有那些被我救了  进了大学的而已
Only the ones that I get out of the life and into college.
那没被救的呢
What about the kids who don't make it?
大概就成了追杀我们的人了
Probably the ones shooting at us.
哪儿也别去
Don't go anywhere.
什么  等等  你去哪
What? Wait. Where--where are you going?
去找个药店
To find us a pharmacy.
你该注意一下
You should be careful
你的胆固醇摄入量了  警探
About your cholesterol intake, detective.
怎么  我们在约会吗
What, are we dating?
弄到我要的情报了吗
Do you have the information I asked you for?
原来你才是老板啊
You're the boss, huh?
电话那一头的神秘男声
The voice on the other end of the phone?
车牌登记在市中心一家皮包公司名下
The plate's registered to a shell corp in midtown.
查不下去了
It's a dead end.
我问你件事
Hey, let me ask you something.
你们到底在追查谁  朋友的朋友先生
Who are you trying to track down, "Mr. Friend of a friend"?
除了俄国人  还有别的犯罪集团
The russians aren't the only criminal operation
在找查理・伯顿
Looking for charlie burton.
你是说这个车牌是以利亚的吗
You saying this plate belongs to Elias?
有可能  你在你的报告里提过
Maybe. You mentioned in your report
被害人死前和伯顿先生说过话
That the victim spoke to mr. Burton before he expired.
什么意思  你读过我的报告
Whoa. What do you mean? You read my report?
-你怎么能读到我的报告  -这无关紧要  弗斯科先生
- How did you read my report? - doesn't matter, mr. Fusco.
重要的是本尼想传达什么讯息
What matters is that whatever message benny was passing along,
这对以利亚很重要
It means a great deal to elias.
你的意思是  俄国人想杀这个可怜虫
so you're telling me the russians want
因为他目击了本尼被杀
The poor bastard dead because he witnessed them taking out benny.
而以利亚也想杀他
And elias wants him dead
因为他认为他手上有重要的情报
Because he thinks he has sensitive information.
-他可真倒霉  -是啊
- Not his lucky day, is it? - indeed.
我要你上报这辆车被盗
That car-- I need you to report it stolen,
然后把报告发到这个电子邮箱
Then email the report number to that address.
你有咱们共同朋友的消息吗
Hey, you heard from our mutual friend?
怎么  你担心起他来了  警探
What, are you worried about him, detective?
只是比较好奇
Let's go with curious.
没有
No.
没他的消息
No word from him.
我今天做的几乎有昨天两倍多
I made almost twice what I did yesterday.
你做的还是没我多
You still ain't made more than me.
伙计们  我能借点毒品吗
Hello, fellas. Can I borrow some of your drugs?
放松点  我不是来打架
oh, no. Easy, fella. I'm not looking for a fight.
看来你是免不了一顿打了
Looks like you found one anyway.
别这样
Don't do it.
我警告你
I'm telling you, now.
谢谢
Thank you.
既然伊万的儿子们卷入了这件事
If ivan's sons are involved in this,
杂货店里的可能就是他本人
Could be the man himself was at the bodega--
亲自为他兄弟复仇
Avenge his brother's death in person.
以利亚的手下两周前杀了他
Elias' crew took him out last week,
还有十几个其他俄国杀手
Along with a half a dozen other russian hitters.
我以为俄国黑帮在布莱顿海滩没人敢动
I thought the russians were untouchable in brighton beach.
以前是  不知以利亚哪里来的情报
They were. No one knows where elias gets his information.
他总能抢在对手和我们前面
He's always one step ahead of all of them...and us.
我还弄不明白
What I still don't get is why elias
为什么以利亚要争夺布莱顿海滩
Is trying to make a move for brighton beach.
1973年有个叫玛琳・以利亚的女人被谋杀了
A woman named Marlene Elias was murdered in 1973.
她跟唐・莫雷蒂有个私生子
She had an illegitimate son with Don Moretti.
我认为以利亚就是唐的儿子
I think Elias is the Don's kid.
莫雷蒂被关押之前
Last place Moretti ran
最后的地盘就是布莱顿海滩
Before he got locked up was Brighton Beach.
所以唐的私生子就回来清场
So the Don's bastard son came back to clean up?
夺回本属于他的一切
Claim his birthright?
那是什么
What is that?
可卡因
Cocaine.
我想凡事总是会有第一次吧
I guess there's a first time for everything.
这是胶水
Is that glue?
是
Yeah.
没什么比两毛五分一瓶的胶水
Nothing like over-the-counter polymer
能更快地愈合伤口的了
To close a wound in a pinch.
你们超人预备班都教这些东西
You learn all this in hero training?
差不多吧
Something like that.
谢谢你
Thank you.
没事
Sure.
不是  说真的
No, really...
谢谢你
Thank you.
如果不是你在  我估计就直接躺了
If it wasn't for you, I'd be dead right now.
以前耍过枪没有
You ever use one of these?
你拿着不是更好嘛
Don't you think it would be better if you kept it?
总要以防万一
Well, just in case.
别  我上一次玩枪
No, last time I touched a gun, I shot cans
跟我的养父出去打易拉罐
With one of my foster dads...
结果意外打死一只鸟
Accidentally killed a bird--
不怎么好的童年回忆
Not my favorite childhood memory.
很简单的  你看
Simple. Look...
这是保险  这样上弹匣
Safety's there. Just load the magazine like this.
拉套筒  很简单
Rack it. Simple.
你真的觉得我们能从这儿出去
Do you really think we'll get out of here?
我们现在出去的把握可比
We have a hell of a lot better chance
20分钟之前的把握要大老多了
Than we did 20 minutes ago.
他们来了
Here they come.
你们是来找那些在我们楼里乱窜的人吗
You after those boys running around our building?
没错
That's right.
他从我的人手里抢了东西
He took something from my people.
我们不给你们麻烦  你们去做了他们
We don't give you any problems, you take 'em out?
成交
I can make that deal.
给另外一个拿一把
Give one to the other guy.
我们帮忙  你们会快上很多
We'll help you out a whole lot quicker.
有人跟我讲他们躲在四楼上
Someone told me they're hiding out on the fourth floor.
有个人还在流血
And one of them's already bleeding.
穿上这个
Put this on.
如果我能找到一条通的电话线
If I can find a line that's still operating,
我们就能打电话
We can make a call.
我以为只有我还在用座机打电话
Wow, I thought I was the only one who still had a hard line.
我还希望这栋楼里的人都能像你一样
I was hoping there was someone in this building
那么传统  查理
As old-fashioned as you, Charlie.
很抱歉把你给牵扯进来了
I'm sorry I got you into this mess.
没事  我就干这个
It's okay. It's my job.
干这行可不安全
It's a dangerous career choice.
这话我今天是第二次听了
That's the second time today I've heard that.
有意思  你让我想到他了
It's funny. You remind me of him.
芬奇  我刚就在跟人说你
Finch... I was just talking about you.
你在哪  里瑟先生
Where are you, Mr. Reese?
廉价房规划区
The double "B" Housing projects--
四楼  北楼
Fourth floor, north tower.
给我找条出去的路  芬奇
Find me a way out of here, Finch--
一条别人都不会走的路
One that no one else will use.
城市规划局应该有蓝图
City planning office should have old blueprints.
伯顿先生状况如何
How is Mr. Burton faring?
受了伤但是命够硬
He's wounded but stubborn.
他能挺过去
He'll pull through.
俄国人不是唯一在追杀他的人
The Russians aren't the only ones after him.
我认为以利亚也在找他
I think Elias is looking for him too.
两条施工通道
Two service entrances--
离你最近的那条在东北边的走廊
The one closest to you is in the northeast corridor.
-能过去吗  -别无选择
- Can you make it there?  - We've got no choice.
告诉弗斯科早上七点11号码头见
Tell Fusco to meet us at pier 11 at 7:00 A.M.
我们会去乘河东渡轮
We'll be on the East River Ferry.
小心点  里瑟先生
Be careful, Mr. Reese.
走吧
Come on.
走到下个走廊后就到施工用楼梯了
Service stairs should be around the next corridor.
眼睛擦亮点  哪里都有可能藏人
Keep your eyes open. They could be anywhere.
我看他们往这边走了
Hey, I think they went this way.
-现在怎么办  -在这等
- What now? - Wait here.
是谁
Who's there?
去那边看看
Check down that way.
-伯顿先生  -威尔
- Mr. Burton?  - Will?
你们在这做什么
What are you doing?
你好  威尔
Hey, Will.
为了抄近路走了进来  结果我们
Came in looking for a shortcut, and we just, uh...
顺便说下  这位是我朋友
This is my friend, by the way.
我们迷路了
We just got lost.
去南边看看
Check the south side.
来吧  我爸爸不在家
Come on. My dad's not home.
你们能进来避避
You can hide in here.
机动车寻回中心
Vehicle Recovery Services.
你好  我是弗斯科警探  警号7645
Yeah, this is Detective Fusco, shield number 7645.
我正在开启一辆遭窃车辆的追踪器
I'm trying to turn on the locator in a stolen vehicle.
报告编号为
Uh, report number is...
L 377
Lima 377.
谢谢  警探  有什么可以效劳
Thank you, Detective. How can I help you?
麻烦你开启车辆的GPS跟踪器
Yeah, could you turn on the car's G.P.S. Locator
以及车内话筒
And the microphone?
当然可以  请稍等
Of course. Bear with me, please.
我以为你跟你爸爸早就搬出去了
I thought you and your dad moved out of here.
还没有  他说一找到工作就马上搬
Not yet. He said we will as soon as he gets a job.
是啊  现在世道不太好
Yeah, times are tough right now.
我相信他很快就能找到
I'm sure he'll get one soon.
只是别搬出我学校的学区之外去了  好吗
Just don't move out of my school district, okay?
-你做作业了  -都做完了
- You did your homework? - Yep. All of it.
-你怎么看  -埃德蒙很不错
- What did you think? - Edmond's cool--
《基督山伯爵》男主人公
他是个幸存者  知道吗
A survivor, you know?
尽管他完成了他的复仇
Even though he got his revenge,
却还是躲不开那些不幸
Some bad stuff still stuck with him.
你是个聪明的孩子  威尔
Yeah, you're a smart kid, Will.
你就是得多来上课
You just need to show up to class more.
我是有努力
I'm trying.
我们每个人都得努力吧
That's all any of us can do, right?
丧尸
Zombies?
它们会占领全宇宙
They're taking over the universe.
嗯  决不能让它们得逞
Yeah, can't have that.
你是谁
Who are you?
你就是那个警察
You're that cop.
听说俄国人在廉价房里
Word is the Russians are inside the double "B"s.
我们得抢先一步找到他们
We better get to them first.
那是不是你  以利亚
Is that you, Elias?
开门  不然我们就进去了
Open up, or we're coming in.
你们想干嘛
What do you want?
小伙子啊  你一个人在家
Hey, little man. You all alone in there?
你说呢
What's it look like?
干嘛不让我进去看看  确认一下
Why don't you let me in, so I can make sure?
我爸爸教我
My papa taught me better
不要随便给陌生人开门
Than to let strangers inside our place,
尤其是出来混的
Especially punks.
-是吗  -就是
- Is that right? - That's right.
他还说盗亦有道  要彼此互相尊重
He also said that vory are supposed to show respect
才行
To one another.
你爸爸是个聪明人
Your papa's a smart man.
好好看家  小朋友
You be good, kid.
谢谢  威尔
Thanks, Will.
小意思  伯顿先生
It's all good, Mr. Burton.
你是我最好的老师
You're the best teacher I've got.
查理
Charlie...
你还能走到施工用楼梯去么
Can you make it to the service stairs?
我可以试试  但止疼药好像药效过了
I'll try, but the painkiller sort of wore off.
你们干嘛不走老的入口走道
Why don't you just use the old entrance?
几年前他们就关掉了施工楼梯
They closed it down a few years ago.
-台阶都烂掉了  -那走道在哪
- The stairs got all rotted. - Where is it?
就在走廊那边
It's--it's down the hall.
就从你们来的方向走回去就是
It's back the way that you came.
谢谢
Thanks.
走吧
Come on.
我欠你个人情
I owe you one.
那明天见了  伯顿先生
I'll see you tomorrow, Mr. Burton.
好  我们明天见
Yeah. Yeah, we'll see you tomorrow.
你们查过走廊了吗
You... did you guys get that hallway?
我们走
Let's go.
开门  否则我们自己进去
Open up, or we're coming in.
有人吗
Hello?
有人在家吗
Anyone home?
别躲了
Can't hide forever.
不管怎么躲  我们都会把你们找出来
Wherever you are, we're gonna find you.
然后你们就玩完了
And then we're gonna end you.
走吧  我们继续搜
Come on. Let's keep moving.
小朋友你掉队咯
Looks like you got left behind.
今晚老夫
How can I help
有什么能帮到两位纽约市警局的贵客
The New York City Police Department tonight?
我们是来找你儿子彼得了解
Your son Peter's wanted for questioning
本尼・达格斯蒂诺谋杀案的有关情况
In the murder of Benny D'Agostino.
知道我们上哪去找他吗
Know where we might find him?
-那个本尼是谁  -省省吧  伊万
- Who is this Benny? - Come on, Ivan.
据我们了解本尼是杀害
We heard Benny was the trigger man
你兄弟的凶手
In your brother's murder.
我们也知道杂货店那件事是报复
And we know the Bodega run was payback.
你们看来知道很多
You seem to know a lot
根本不用到我这里来问问题嘛
For someone who is here to ask me questions.
约格洛夫先生  我们不想要再多的血腥了
Mr. Yogorov, we don't want any more bloodshed.
彼得今天一天都在这里工作
My Peter was here working all day long.
他去储藏室为今晚的宴会
He's at the storage getting more wine
挑酒去了
For an event tonight.
恕我直言  先生
With all due respect, Sir,
你并不怎么适合给你儿子做不在场证明
You may not be the best person to give your son an alibi.
如果你们来是为了给彼得按罪名的话
If you are here to accuse my Peter of something,
我建议你们去拿个逮捕令再来
I suggest you come back with a warrant...
前提还得是你们能弄到
If you can get one.
伊万  这场战争没有赢家
There are no winners in this war, Ivan--
只会死人
Only dead soldiers.
你是不是准备连你的儿子们都要葬送掉
Are you ready to lose your sons too?
假设我知道你们所说的是什么事情
If I knew to what you were referring,
我敢说这个所谓的战争
I'd say that this so-called war
也是那个孬种以利亚挑起来  不是我
Was started by this coward Elias, not me.
他才是那个到我的地盘上来撒野的人
He's the one who comes to my neighborhood...
偷我的东西  还杀我的人
Stealing from me, killing my people...
不是我
Not the other way around.
失陪了  我还要去主持宴会
Now, if you excuse me, I have an event to host.
请吧
Please.
不介意我借用一下吧
Mind if I borrow this for a moment?
去死吧你
Screw you.
用这种语气对劫匪说话可不明智啊  拉斯洛
It's a bad move to insult your hostage taker, Laszlo.
闭上你的嘴  不然我让你永远没法说话
Keep your mouth shut, or I'll shut it permanently.
走
Let's go.
芬奇  是我
Finch, it's me.
通知卡特  杂货店的枪手
Get word to Carter that her bodega shooters
就在廉价房里
are inside the Double"B"s.
没问题
Of course.
我会确保让弗斯科警探
And I'll make sure detective Fusco meets you
在码头同你和证人碰头
And the witness at the ferry.
你先走
You first.
-我们现在去哪  -渡河
- Where are we going now? - Across the river.
快点  拉斯洛  快走
Come on, Laszlo, let's move.
刚收到短信  他往11号码头去了
Just got a text. He's heading to pier 11.
赶紧过去拦住他
Let's get over there to intercept him, now.
-干得不错啊  警探  -彼此彼此  卡特
- Nice collar, detective. - You too, Carter.
-知道是谁报的警吗  -当然
- You find out who called it in? - I have an idea.
喂  我是弗斯科
Yeah. Fusco.
我还以为
And I was just starting to believe
我们能信任你了  警探
That we could trust you, detective.
我很失望
I'm disappointed.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
以利亚的人过来了
Elias' men are on their way
准备到码头对付我们的朋友
To meet our friends at the ferry.
-他们怎么知道  -我还想问你呢
- How the hell'd they find out? - I was going to ask you.
-你觉得是我的错吗  -不然会是谁
- You're blaming me for this? - Then who told them?
听着  我不可能...
Listen, there's no way I would've--
警探  你还在吗
Detective, are you there?
我把你送过河后
When we get you across the river,
我会把你交给我的警探朋友
I'm going to hand you off to my detective.
你可以信任他
Now, you can trust him.
查理  你必须出面作证
Charlie, I need you to testify.
有一件事我能确定
One thing I know for sure--
在经历过昨晚这么多事情后
After everything we went through last night,
我不能让这些混蛋再在我的城市
I don't want to see these cretins running around my town
横行霸道了
Ever again.
谢谢
Thanks.
你准备好招了吗
Ready to talk?
你准备好放我走了吗
You ready to let me go?
彼得  监控拍到你了
Peter, we got you on camera.
还有证人说
We've got witnesses that say
你和你兄弟在布莱顿海滩
You and your brother were shooting up the streets
的马路上开枪打人
In brighton beach.
不知道你在说什么
No idea what you're talking about.
多么美好的早晨啊
It's a beautiful morning.
我必须谢谢你  约翰
I have to thank you, John.
实话告诉你
To tell you the truth,
我以为自己看不到太阳了
I didn't think I'd see another one.
以利亚杀了你叔叔
Elias killed your uncle.
你和你父亲  还有你兄弟
You, your father, and your brother
去杂货店想找他报仇
Went to the bodega for revenge.
你不知道以利亚长什么样
You didn't know what Elias looked like,
所以他的副手  本尼・达格斯蒂诺
So his lieutenant Benny D'agostino
成了二号目标
Was the next best thing.
而现在  你又要除掉那个证人
And now you're trying to rub out the witness--
他看到了你父亲的脸
The guy who saw your father's face.
我们得到消息
We heard from a source
说以利亚那晚会出现在
That Elias was supposed to be at the bodega
-那个杂货店  -他在和本尼会面
- That night. - he was meeting Benny.
是的
Yeah.
但我们到那的时候
But when we showed up...
只看到本尼一个人
Benny was all we saw.
直到杂货店店主告诉了我们真相
Found out what really went down after the owner called us.
他说还有个人
He said there was another guy.
你算是什么人
Hey, what are you--
贪污的条子
Corrupt P.D.,
还是雇佣兵
Gun for hire?
那种拿人钱财
What kind of guy takes money
保护你主子那种人渣的人吗
To protect a scumbag like your boss here?
你觉得他会作证吗
You think he's going to testify...
在他做了那一切之后
After everything he's done?
他把这个地方搅得鸡犬不宁
He's tearing this town apart.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
你不知道他是谁吧
You don't know who he is, do you...
也不知道他的能耐
What he's capable of?
你还不明白吗
You don't really get it, do you?
你真以为我们这么大费周章
You honestly think we'd go to all this trouble
只为除掉一个证人吗
For a witness?
你现在陷入的局面
You're in the middle of a situation
连你自己都没搞清楚
That you don't even understand.
别逼我开枪  约翰
Don't make me shoot you, John.
扔下枪  踢过来  拜托了
Drop your weapon and kick it to me, please.
我以为你不喜欢枪
I thought you didn't like guns.
有时候你必须做你不喜欢做的事
You know, sometimes you have to do things you don't like.
包括教你仇家的孩子历史吗
Like teaching history to the children of your enemies?
三年来  我观察着他们
Three years, I watched them--
教导那些猪猡人渣们的孩子
Cleaning up after the children of those pigs.
这些时间足够去了解
It's a good amount of time to learn
你的敌人最在意什么  弱点是什么
What makes your enemies tick, what makes them weak.
你能知道那些人们想藏起来的秘密
You know all the secrets you and your family tried to hide,
拉斯洛  就你的亲生骨肉告诉我的事
Laszlo, I learned all about from your own flesh and blood?
我知道你孩子就和我一样恨你
Your children hate you almost as much as I do.
把你自己绑到栏杆上  约翰
Tie yourself to the railing, John,
绑牢了
Nice and tight.
我知道你有多擅长
I know how capable you are
让自己脱离险境
Of getting out of difficult situations.
跪下
On your knees, please.
那天你是在杂货店和本尼碰面
You were meeting Benny at the bodega that day,
是吧
Weren't you?
那些杀手的目标是你
The shooters were looking for you.
是的  这是别人不知道你是谁
Yeah, the benefits of no one knowing who you are
或是你长什么样的好处
Or what you look like.
不过我想现在这个优势没了
That's gone now, I suppose.
是时候该转移了
It's time to evolve.
我已经做好下一步准备
I'm ready for the next step.
开枪啊
Go ahead.
要我看到你做我城市的老大  我宁愿死
I'd rather die than see you running my city.
你知道本尼死前说了什么吗
You know what Benny said before he died?
他说  [拉丁语][恺撒大帝的名言]
He said, "Veni, vidi, vici"--
"我来  我见  我征服"
I came, I saw, I won.
他说你们强大的俄罗斯黑帮已经不堪一击
He said your almighty Bratva was already crumbling.
他说我们已经胜券在握
He said we'd already won.
这是本尼的债
This is for Benny.
以利亚  要是你杀了他...
Elias, if you kill him...
我不会杀了他
I'm not going to kill him. -
我不过是传达个信息
I'm just going to send a message.
告诉你们老大  拉斯洛  如果他今晚滚出城
You tell your papa, Laszlo, if he gets out of town tonight,
我就放过他
I'll let him live.
布莱顿海滩现在归我了
Brighton beach belongs to me now.
我想过是不是要杀你  约翰
I thought about killing you, John.
但我觉得这样太忘恩负义了
But I realize that that would seem ungrateful.
况且  我怎么舍得杀死你这种人才
Besides, how do you take the life of someone so talented?
我需要你这样的人
I could really use a guy like you in my organization.
祝你好运  约翰
I wish you luck, John.
我们以后大可以井水不犯河水
If you stay out of my way, I'll stay out of yours.
不然呢
What if I don't?
那我们再见面时  就不会像现在这么友好了
Then we'll meet again under less pleasant circumstances.
你现在相信我了
You believe me now?
不好意思  警探
I'm sorry, detective.
见到你真好  莱奈尔
Nice to see you, Lionel.
你的犯人被绑在栏杆上呢
Your suspect is tied to the railing.
跟他说声不客气
Tell him "You're welcome."
查理的事是个意外
Couldn't have known about Charlie.
机器跳出了他的号码  因为他是目标
The machine found a man who was targeted for death.
我们只是不知道  他同时又是个杀手
We just didn't know that he was also a killer.
被他跑了是我的错  芬奇
It's my fault he's out there, Finch.
不是你一个人的错
It's not yours alone.
我们刚刚救的男人
We just saved a man
他的人生只有复仇
Whose only goal in life is revenge.
他花了这么多年  通过孩子
He spent years studying his enemies
来了解仇家的一举一动
Through their own children.
约翰  我们的信息不完整
John, we have limited information.
我们从一开始就知道  我们也可能会犯错
We knew when we began this that we might make mistakes.
但我们得走了
But we have to go now.
我们还要帮助更多人  还会有更多号码
We have more people to help-- more numbers.
又会有多少号码跳出来
and how many of those numbers will come up
就因为我们救了一个不该救的人
Because we saved one man's life?
老大
Boss...
完事了
It's done.
不  这只是个开始
No, it's just beginning.
我来  我见  我征服
Veni, vidi, vici.
疑犯追踪 第1季 第7集
Person of Interest S01E07 720p HDTV x264
字幕翻译：YYeTs人人影视